Sooner or later, someone will pay the price.
Drugstore Cowboy is a drama, crime film directed by Gus Van Sant.
Portland, Oregon, 1971.
Bob Hughes is the charismatic leader of a peculiar quartet, formed by his wife, Dianne, and another couple, Rick and Nadine, who
skillfully steal from drugstores and hospital medicine cabinets in order to appease their insatiable need for drugs.
But neither fun nor luck last forever.
Bob, played by Matt Dillon.
Dianne, played by Kelly Lynch.
Gentry, played by James Remar.
Rick, played by James LeGros.
Nadine, played by Heather Graham.
Drug Counselor, played by Beah Richards.
Drugstore Cowboy is a 1989 American black comedy film directed by Gus Van Sant.
Written by Van Sant and Daniel Yost and based on an autobiographical novel by James Fogle,
the film stars Matt Dillon, Kelly Lynch, James LeGros, and Heather Graham.
It features supporting performances from James Remar, Max
Perlich, Grace Zabriskie, and William S.
Based on the then-unpublished novel of the same name by James Fogle, it
follows a group of nomadic drug addicts in 1971 Portland, Oregon.
It was Van Sant's second film as director, following his 1988 debut Mala Noche.
Principal photography of Drugstore Cowboy took
place in Portland in the fall of 1988.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on October 6, 1989.
It received significant acclaim from film critics, with praise for its
performances, realistic portrayal of drug addiction, and its dark humor.
It received numerous accolades from film critic associations, including three
nominations and four wins at the Independent Spirit Awards.
In the years since its original release, the film
has developed a cult following.
The film explores themes of drug abuse, support
group, 1970s, drug addiction, junkie.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.